Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2006
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Haupt, Irene
1 box (52 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 52 print photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2006 at the University at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2006.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
The photographic prints were made from digital photograph files. Two CD-ROMS are stored with the collection. They contain JPEG format versions of the original digital photographs. One CD consists of a folder marked "jpegs for web" with images slightly altered for online use.
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2000 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006 contains 52 images of participants in the festival for 2006. The list of musicians includes David Felder, Bernard Rands, Gunther Schuller, Charles Wuorinen, David Taylor, Harvey Sollberger, Nicholas Isherwood, and Tony Arnold.
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Magnus Andersson, guitarist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 1)
- Tony Arnold and Jayn Rosenfeld, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 2)
- Tony Arnold, soprano, June 2006, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 3)
- Tony Arnold, soprano, and Movses Pogossian, violinist, in rehearsal of Kurtag's Kafka Fragments, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 4)
- James Avery, conductor, and John Berners, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 5)
- James Baker, conductor of the New York New Music Ensemble, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 6)
- Stefano Bassanese at sound console, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 7)
- Stefano Bassanese and J. T. Rinker at sound console, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 8)
- Stefano Bassanese with hand gesture, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 9)
- Kathleen Chastain, flutist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
- Beverley Ellis, violoncello and Sonja Inglefield, harp, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
- David Felder, seated, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
- David Felder, composer, and Elliot Caplan, filmmaker, June 2006, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
- Thomas Fitzgerald, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
- Stephen Gosling, pianist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
- Charles Haupt, violinist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
- Nicholas Isherwood, baritone, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
- Nicholas Isherwood, baritone, June 2006, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
- Nicholas Isherwood, baritone, with projected image of himself in background, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
- Nicholas Isherwood, baritone, with projected image of himself in background, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
- Nicholas Isherwood, baritone, profile, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
- Nicholas Isherwood, baritone, lower right, with projected image of himself in background, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
- Sven Thomas Kiebler, conducting, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
- Movses Pogossian, violinist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
- Bernard Rands, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
- Bernard Rands, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
- Bernard Rands, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
- Bernard Rands, composer, with James Avery, conductor, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
- Bernard Rands, composer, June 2006, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 29)
- Jayn Rosenfeld, flutist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 30)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 31)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 32)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 33)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 34)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 35)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 36)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 37)
- Gunther Schuller, composer, June 2006, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 38)
- Harvey Sollberger, conducting, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 39)
- Harvey Sollberger, holding Charles Wuorinen score, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 40)
- Harvey Sollberger playing flute, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 41)
- Harvey Sollberger playing flute, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 42)
- Harvey Sollberger (conductor), Tony Arnold (soprano), and members of the New York New Music Ensemble: Chris Finckel (violoncellist), Linda Quan (violinist), and Jayn Rosenfeld (flutist), June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 43)
- Ensemble SurPlus, with conductor James Avery: Christian Kemper, oboe, Sven Thomas Kiebler, piano, Charles Haupt, violin, Stefan Haussler, violin, James Avery, Bodo Friedrich, viola, Beverley Ellis, violoncello, Friedrich Wagner, clarinet, Martina Roth, flute, Olaf Tzschoppe, percussion, Sonja Inglefield, harp, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 44)
- David Taylor, trombonist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 45)
- David Taylor, trombonist, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 46)
- David Taylor, trombonist, with Charles Wuorinen, composer, Harvey Sollberger, conductor, Stephen Gosling, pianist, and members of the Slee Sinfonietta, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 47)
- Augusta Read Thomas, composer, with conductor James Avery and violinist Mosves Pogossian, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 48)
- Charles Wuorinen, composer, with trombonist David Taylor, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 49)
- Charles Wuorinen, composer with conductor James Avery, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 50)
- Charles Wuorinen, composer with conductor Harvey Sollberger, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 51)
- Charles Wuorinen, composer with trombonist David Taylor and violinist Charles Haupt, June 2006, 1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 52)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2000
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 20
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.